Tom A Steinman

IT professional with over 12 years of experience in customer support, system development, and project management. As a Computer Science major proficient in Python, C++, and AGILE/SCRUM processes, I'm seeking software engineering positions that complement my ongoing bachelor's degree studies that offer the opportunity for full-time employment at graduation. Obtains an active US Secret clearance.

Areas of Expertise

- Python, C++, Qt, unit testing
- Runtime Efficiency- Big O, Omega, Theta
- Data structures and algorithms
- Windows 2000/XP/7/8/10/11

Professional Experience

Broadleaf Inc / ASRC Federal | Manassas, VA

Lead Technician (02/2018 - 03/2020, 09/2021 - Current)

- Manage the relocation, installation, de-installation, and repair of computers, servers, switches, networking, patching and audio/visual devices
- Supervise up to 24 temporary and part-time employees
- Collaboration with Network Engineers and government employees as an on-site contact, assisting with programming and reconfiguring switches
- Maintaining security and confidentiality adhering to US Secret clearance

Reliasource | Baltimore, MD

Lead Technician / Field Engineer (07/2010 - 03/2020, 6/2022 - Current)

- Conduct site surveys in coordination with government employees
- Installation of VoIP system hardware and maintained 66 block and overhead paging systems
- IT ticket usage

Education

Oak Park High School | Kansas City, MO College Preparatory Degree

University of Missouri-Kansas City | BA in Computer Science | Expected Graduation: 12/2024

Honors Student | 4.0 GPA

Github Repository

https://github.com/tasn78?tab=repositories

Education in progress

C# .Net, SQL, Front-end software engineering with Qt, Java and Blazor